SHIVAM PATEL

shivampatel@utexas.edu 201 East 21st St M0916 • Austin, Texas 78664 • (319) 651-6181

PROFILE

Ambitious, detail-oriented professional with corporate experience in Software Development. Strong written and verbal communication skills, eager to lead and be immersed within development projects. Spent last three years volunteering by tutoring underprivileged students in local high school district in Math and Science topics.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin Computer Science, Major

Aspiring Certificate: Networks & Information Security

Overall GPA: -.-

Relevant Coursework: Linear Algebra, Intro to

Programming, and Logical Reasoning

Organizations: Mobile Application Development,

Information & Security Systems Society

College of DuPage Supplementary Coursework - 10 Credit Hours 2014 - 2016

Overall GPA: 4.0

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sonne Industries - Light Sentry Department - Application Development Intern; Naperville, Illinois Startup Corporation - Developed Residential Lighting Automation System through Sun Dependency

June 2015 - January 2016

May 2020

- Captured requirements and Developed mobile application outline for multi-platform development of company product
- Organized application outline by implementing features of Xcode (iOS Interactive Development Environment)
- Conducted market research through an international survey to bolster company product and increase market penetration
- Increased Market and Exposure of company on multiple media platforms

 Increased market penetration of social media domains by 40%
- Attended corporate training sessions to familiarize with Light Sentry modules

Shivam Services LLC - Owner and President; Naperville, Illinois

July 2016 - Present

- Developed math and science intuition through educational tutoring sessions
- Developing website for Tutoring Marketing and E-Commerce
- Integrated HTML, CSS, and Javascript technology for web development
- Logistical Manager of Corporate Activities

Kumon Math & Reading Center - Math Tutor and Mentor; Plainfield, Illinois

May 2014 - November 2014

- Assisted students in understanding Mathematical Concepts such as Calculus and Trigonometry
- Explained complex concepts in small group setting; graded assignments and examinations
- Mentored students beyond academic domains
- Implemented organizational strategy for student logistics

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Business Professionals of America - Vice President

August 2015 - May 2016

- Leader of 150+ member organization for developing business and technical skills
- Organized and Facilitated Large scale events for cross school district Business Professionals of America Chapters
- 3-Time National Competitor in Web Site Design, Global Marketing, Accounting

Peer2Peer Tutoring Non-Profit Organization - Co-Founder

May 2014 - May 2016

- Founded a tutoring organization to help students in school district pursue educational endeavors through volunteer tutors
- Facilitated tutoring sessions for an array of students Logistical Analysis
- Mentored several students in various Math & Science disciplines
- Developed website for marketing purposes and increased market exposure in local area

HONORS

- Summa Cum Laude Honors
 - ◆ Graduated in Top 2% of High School Class
- 2nd Place National Champion for Web Site Design Business Professionals of America
- 2nd Place National Champion in Global Marketing Business Professionals of America

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Computer Skills: Java, XCode (Basic), Python (Basic), MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint

Languages: Conversational in Gujarati

Interests: Industry Technology Developments, Personal Growth Reading, Tutoring in Math and Science Disciplines

Work Eligibility: US Citizen